Guide to the British Fascist, Anti-Fascist, and Anti-Semitic Printed Ephemera Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
British fascist, anti-fascist, and anti-Semitic printed ephemera collection
1905-1963
MS 1886
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.25
Collection of materials documenting British fascist, anti-fascist, and anti-Semitic political movements in the mid-twentieth century. Includes pamphlets, leaflets, and serially published newspapers and magazines produced by organizations such as the British Empire Union, British League, British Union of Fascists, Jewish People's Council Against Fascism and Anti-Semitism, and Trades Advisory Council. Also includes a small group of rare Muslim anti-fascist leaflets.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased by the Judaica Collection from Fishburn Books, 2006. Transferred to Manuscripts and Archives, 2007
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically, either by organization name or by topic.
Scope and Contents
Collection of materials documenting British fascist, anti-fascist, and anti-Semitic political movements in the mid-twentieth century. Includes pamphlets, leaflets, and serially published newspapers and magazines produced by organizations such as the British Empire Union, British League, British Union of Fascists, Jewish People's Council Against Fascism and Anti-Semitism, and Trades Advisory Council. Also includes a small group of rare Muslim anti-fascist leaflets.
Anti-fascist movements -- Great Britain; Antisemitism -- Great Britain; Fascism -- Great Britain
- Inventory
  - Organizations
    - British Empire Union, The Empire Record, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - British League, British League Review, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - British Union of Fascists, Circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Hoffmann, H. R., News from Germany, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Imperial Fascist League, Circa 1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Jewish People's Council Against Fascism and Anti-Semitism, Circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - National Socialist League, Circa 1937-Circa 1939 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - National Workers' Party of Great Britain, Circa 1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - New Europe Group, Circa 1939 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Trades Advisory Council, TAC (publication), 1941-1949 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Topics
    - Anti-fascist leaflets by unknown Muslim organizations, Circa 1930s-Circa 1940s (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Anti-fascist printed ephemera, Circa 1930s-Circa 1940s (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Anti-Semitic printed ephemera, Circa 1905-Circa 1940s (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Assorted fascist, anti-fascist, and anti-Semitic newspapers, 1936-1963 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Assorted printed ephemera reflecting political opinions of the period, Circa 1930s-Circa 1940s (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - British anti-war printed ephemera, Circa 1938-Circa 1945 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Jewish and Christian responses to anti-Semitism, Circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 16)